

BRENDA SALINAS

FSQA Supervisor



Professional Summary

Experienced Quality Assurance Specialist with talents in reducing production costs by improving manufacturing practices and reviewing and auditing records. Efficient in creating programs for employees to maintain quality standards. Excellent computer skills to manage QA standards and team members.



Education

2013-08 -2018-05

Bachelor of Science: Biological and Agricultural Engineering

Texas A&M University - College Station, TX

Minor in Mathematics



Work History

2019-04 -Current

Quality Assurance Supervisor

Sovos Brands Intermediate, Inc, Austin, TX

- Participated on project to reduce 10% of customer complaints on the course of one year.
- Re-evaluated production line to relocate people applying lean manufacturing methodology to save 15% on supply cost.
- Led operational meetings with production team to review opportunities for improvement.
- Restructured shift operations to complete work content.
- Commissioned new production lines, new SKUs, and re-evaluation existing SKUs to ensure smooth transition.
- Improved and optimized SOP, SSOP and Preventive Controls.
- Participated on installation and optimization of new equipment and how it affects current HACCP program.
- Led in root cause analysis in food safety defects, and implementation of corrective actions.
- Managed QA standards of 14 employees for over 2 years.

2018-11 -2019-04

Quality Assurance Supervisor

Frankie V's Kitchen, Dallas, TX

- Participated in root-cause analysis and corrective action/preventative action (CAPA) implementation.
- Led cross-functional lines of production.
- Developed and implemented HACCP program, CCPs and preventive controls for new fresh produce project.
- Developed and launched new production line of fresh produce for the company.
- Installed and optimized new equipment for new fresh produce production.



Address

Austin, TX, 78703

Phone

(512) 514-5091

E-mail

Brenda.salinas2128@gmail.com



Skills

Quality Assurance
Production optimization
Auditing systems
Vendor and Client Relations
Correction action planning
Warehouse safety operations

Change management

Data collection and analysis Statistics concepts



Leadership

- Active contributor of the annual SQF Audit team.
- Developed and presented monthly food safety trainings to all employees on the company.
- Led a Quality assurance technician crew of 14 team members per shift.

Safety Committee Chairperson

- Developed recommendations to reduce hazards by improving procedures.
- Identified incident causes and optimal prevention strategies by conduction of root cause investigations.



Certifications

Lean Green Belt

Implementing SQF Systems

Practical HACCP for food processors



Native Spanish, Fluent English